Ken Ren

North York, ON M2M 4H9 ken.ren98@gmail.com +1 647 832 6173

Computer Science bachelor from York University, having solid foundation on Java, JavaScript and Python coding, also familiar with C / C++. Worked with Spring Framework and MERN stack on multiple project. Positive and communicative participant during team work. Very familiar with software deployment, operation and networking. Very familiar with virtual environment, cloud environment and all three major types of OS and related automation tools - FreeBSD, Linux (Both Fedora and Debian Based branches) and Windows family. Also, Having handful experience with Docker and LXC / LXD. And extra experiences with Computer Vision / Machine Learning / Computer Graphics and Computer Security including topics like Neural Networks, Image Processing, Programmable Shaders, Code analysis and Penetration testing, etc.

Highly skilled technician offering 5+ years experience of part-time Computer building and repairing, capable of repairing Laptop / PC / MacBook / Cellphone / iPhone up to component level. Also, familiar with all kinds of hardware / consumer electronic, their advantages, and disadvantages, keep updated all the time. Versatile media professional, hosting multiple hardware review / product demonstration channels with over 20,000 subscribers in total. Equipped with knowledge of different workflows of vary industries and consumers. Having a strong communication skill, assisting customers with their technical issues, and helping them find the right product effectively, sold more than 2000 computers over last 3 years. Having a handful firsthand experience with BIOS / UEFI and Driver issues, familiar with all kinds of protocols and form factors. Also being able to explain the fundamental organization of computer system to a certain degree.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Personal Details

Highest Level of Education: Bachelor's Degree

Total years of experience: 4

Work Experience

Part-time Technician

Mr.Leaves Electronics and Net Woking Inc. October 2021 to Present

- Server Sale, Rental and Maintenance
- Cloud Service development, deployment and Maintenance
- (Alibaba, Tencent, AWS, Azure)
- Special System Building for Mining and Machine Learning purpose (Linux/BSD Based)
- Automation Development and Deployment for small to medium sized business
- · Home/Business networking design and deployment
- PC design / build / repair / resell, PC component resell and repair

Part-time Hardware Review Youtuber

Self Employment - Toronto, ON

Present

/ Since September 2018, Video Channel Paused Since Jan 2022

- Making hardware unboxing / review and tutorial videos
- Receive sponsorship and review unit from companies
- Running several video channels in different platform (Mostly in Chinese)
- Started making bilingual videos in late 2020
- Running a personal forum and some game servers
- BLOG URL: https://www.mr-leaves.com
- Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpFqOU0-8xrGOaREzaK93oA
- Bilibili: https://space.bilibili.com/33069720
- Xigua: https://www.toutiao.com/c/user/token/

 $MS4wLjABAAAASN4ECKte3p26j5wKrOxyWbDg0ML_24Nz2_IOivr50e1-$

03bdz0d1u rD5BBoYPSS/

Part-time Computer Technician

Self Employment - Toronto, ON

September 2015 to September 2021

- PC design / build / repair / resell
- Laptop repair / refurbish / resell
- Apple product repair/ upgrade, Clover/OpenCore EFI configuring
- Software problems resolve
- Network structure design
- Multi-purpose home server design and deploy (VM QEMU / Proxmox VE / LXC Container/ Docker applications / VMware)
- TrueNas / Unraid ZFS deployment experiences

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

York University - Toronto, ON January 2019 to April 2023

Skills

- MySQL
- Java
- · Microsoft SQL Server
- VMWare
- Docker
- NGFW
- Proxmox
- C/C++
- Scripting

- Linux
- Computer networking
- TCP/IP
- Computer Science
- Operating Systems
- BSD
- SQL
- Shell Scripting
- DHCP
- DNS
- Git
- Apache
- Microsoft Windows Server
- APIs

Languages

- Chinese Advanced
- English Advanced

Links

https://github.com/KenRen98